{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "This man rejected his status as a leader by saying “if you are looking for a Moses to lead you out of this capitalist wilderness, you will stay right where you are.” In the aftermath of the Panic of 1893, this man, with the ARU, organized the Pullman Strike. This founding member of the IWW was jailed for telling young men to resist the draft. For ten points, name this Socialist who ran for President four times, the last of which while he was in prison.",
      "answer": "Eugene V. Debs"
    },
    {
      "question": "When told that the Pinochet regime killed 3,000 people, this leader responded by saying it “should have killed more” in a Vera article. This leader, who shared a meme disparaging the appearance of Emmanuelle Macron’s wife survived a 2018 stabbing by Adelio Bispo de Oliveira while campaigning against Fernando Haddad. This man became a front-runner in the 2018 election after Lula da Silva was arrested. Michel Temer was succeeded by, for ten points, what current President of Brazil?",
      "answer": "Jair Bolsonaro"
    },
    {
      "question": "This novel’s protagonist adopts the daughter of his brother-in-law and Yugao [yoo-gah-oh]; his own daughter, the younger Akashi Lady, becomes an empress after being adopted by the protagonist’s wife. Although his father arranges for him to marry the daughter of the Minister of the Left, Lady Aoi [ah-oh-ee], this novel’s title “Shining Prince” pursues Lady Fujitsubo [foo-jee-tsoo-boh] because of her resemblance to his mother. For ten points, name this Japanese novel of the Heian period [hay-ahn period] written by Murasaki Shikibu [moo-rah-sah-kee shee-kee-boo].",
      "answer": [
        "The Tale of Genji",
        "Genji monogatari"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "In this city, 152 searchlights were aimed toward the sky to create a “Theater of Light.” A series of 1935 laws named for this city barred Jews from holding citizenship. Leni Riefenstahl’s Triumph of the Will documents rallies held in this city. During an event in this city, several Nazis told Robert Jackson they were “just following orders.” For ten points, name this German city where several postwar trials were held.",
      "answer": "Nuremberg"
    },
    {
      "question": "This party twice nominated Charles Pinckney for President, with Pinckney soundly losing both times. During the War of 1812, this party lost much of its public support after renouncing the war at the Hartford Convention. One member of this party wrote the First Report on the Public Credit in his role as the first Secretary of the Treasury. For ten points, name this party supported by Alexander Hamilton, the early rival of the Democratic-Republicans.",
      "answer": "Federalist Party"
    },
    {
      "question": "A rebellious general established a ruling dynasty in this empire after winning the Battle of Anfao. Ibn al-Mukhtar chronicled the early monarchs of this empire in his Tarikh al-fattash. The Dendi Kingdom formed out of the collapse of this empire. At the Battle of Tondibi, this empire launched a stampede of cattle in a failed attempt to defeat Judar Pasha’s Moroccan forces. Askia Muhammad led, for ten points, what rival of Mali, a West African empire led from Gao?",
      "answer": [
        "Songhai",
        "Songhay"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Production of these works was suspended during World War II until 1944, when the Allies requested a reprint of its 1939 French issue for its highly detailed maps. This publication ignored Los Angeles for a decade until 2019, when it released an updated California edition; that work cited seven locations, including The French Laundry by Thomas Keller, as “worth a special detour,” its highest rating. For ten points, name this red-covered guide that awards up to three stars to exceptional restaurants and was originally intended to increase sales for its namesake tire company.",
      "answer": "Michelin Guides"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the Observatory Affair, this man was accused of staging an assassination attempt against himself in a publicity stunt. This man removed his country’s death penalty through the Badinter Act. Operation Satanique, the 1985 bombing of the Greenpeace vessel Rainbow Warrior, was authorized by this man. This leader shared power in a cohabitation agreement with his successor, Jacques Chirac. For ten points, name this Socialist President of France.",
      "answer": "Francois Mitterand"
    },
    {
      "question": "This legislation was opposed by the “Stop Taking Our Privileges” campaign organized by Phyllis Schlafly. A version of this legislation was brought to Congress in 1923 by Alice Paul and Crystal Eastman. In 1975, this amendment stalled after only 35 of the required 38 states ratified it. For ten points, name this failed 1970s amendment meant to give equal legal rights to both sexes in the United States.",
      "answer": [
        "Equal Rights Amendment",
        "ERA"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "The Gotjawal Forest is located in this country on an island where government forces killed tens of thousands of people in the late 1940s to suppress a communist uprising. This country’s Chemulpo Bay was the site of the opening shots of the Russo-Japanese War. The Jeju Uprising took place in this country, where American forces landed at Incheon in 1950 to launch an offensive against its northern neighbor. For ten points, name this Asian country on the southern side of a demilitarized zone, whose capital is Seoul.",
      "answer": "South Korea"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "During this conflict, 16 inmates at Rawson Penitentiary were killed in the Trelew Massacre. A series of kidnappings during this conflict was called the Night of the Pencils. Near the end of this conflict, the National Reorganization Process seized control of the country. The Casa Rosada was bombed during this conflict as part as massive unrest in Buenos Aires. For ten points, name this 1974 to 1983 conflict between Marxist and Peronist factions in Argentina.",
        "answer": "Dirty War"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "During the Dirty War, grandmothers gathered in this main square in Buenos Aires to protest the disappearances of their relatives.",
        "answer": [
          "Plaza de Mayo",
          "May Square"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This faith’s goddess Erzulie, a spirit most associated with love and beauty, is said to protect its gay and lesbian members. A rattle called an asson is often used by houngans and mambos in this faith. St. Anthony the Hermit, a sixth century monk from France, is often compared to this faith’s Papa Legba, one of its Loa spirits. For ten points, name this syncretic faith, prominent in Haiti and Louisiana, that is commonly associated with a namesake “doll.”",
        "answer": [
          "Voodoo",
          "Vodou",
          "Vodoun"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Voodoo developed in Haiti during its time as this French colony, which existed from 1659 to 1804.",
        "answer": "Saint-Domingue"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This colony’s economy boomed thanks to Eliza Lucas Pinckney’s indigo plantations. Blackbeard once blockaded and ransomed this colony’s capital for a chest of medicine. In this colony, a man named Cato led America’s largest slave revolt, the Stono Rebellion. British forces withdrew from this colony after defeats at the Battles of King’s Mountain and Cowpens. For ten points, name this American colony governed from Charleston.",
        "answer": "South Carolina"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "During the American Revolution, British forces gained control of South Carolina after this decisive 1780 battle, which ended the military career of Horatio Gates.",
        "answer": "Battle of Camden"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The political structure of this city was weakened by Ferdinand I who carried out his “Blood Judgment,” killing many of its leaders and putting it under direct imperial control. Social Democrats in this city launched the July Revolt, which led to the rise of the Heimwehr. After his success at the Battle of Mohacs [moh-hotch], Suleiman the Magnificent spearheaded an effort to capture this city in 1529. For ten points, name this city, the target of two Ottoman sieges, the center of Hapsburg Austria.",
        "answer": [
          "Vienna",
          "Wien"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "One of the Ottoman sieges of Vienna was countered by these Polish cavalry units originally comprised of exiled Serbians.",
        "answer": [
          "Winged Hussars",
          "Polish Hussars"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In the aftermath of this event, four people, including George Engel, sang La Marseillaise as they walked to the gallows. August Spies and Samuel Fielden gave speeches during this event which was interrupted, possibly by secret Pinkerton agents. The Second International created International Workers” Day to commemorate this event. During this event, hundreds of workers, striking for an 8-hour work day, were wounded by a dynamite bomb. For ten points, name this 1886 labor riot in a namesake Chicago square.",
        "answer": "Haymarket Square Riot"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Haymarket Square Riot heavily damaged the reputation of this labor union founded by Uriah Smith Stephens.",
        "answer": [
          "Knights of Labor",
          "Noble and Holy Order of the Knights of Labor"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This state contains a clonal colony of quaking aspen called Pando that is the heaviest known organism. In 1970, Robert Smithson built a 1,500 foot long earthwork sculpture titled Spiral Jetty in this state’s largest body of water. Paiute [PIE-yoot] Indians killed members of a wagon train in the Mountain Meadows Massacre in what is now this state. The Bonneville Salt Flats and the largest saltwater lake in the Western Hemisphere are located in, for ten points, what western US state that earned its statehood after reforms by its Mormon settlers?",
        "answer": "Utah"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This southwest Utah national park, which contains the Kolob Arch and the Virgin River, was given a biblical name by Mormon settlers.",
        "answer": "Zion National Park"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The Treaty of Wallingford guaranteed this king’s ascension to the throne and ended a conflict involving his mother, Empress Matilda. Following this man’s death, his son joined with Frederick Barbarossa and Philip Augustus on the Third Crusade. This king allegedly asked, “will no one rid me of this meddlesome priest,” prompting four knights to carry out an assassination in Canterbury Cathedral in 1170. For ten points, name this king of England who fathered Richard the Lionheart and John.",
        "answer": "Henry II of England"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "By despairing about the “meddlesome priest,” Henry II essentially ordered the murder of this Archbishop of Canterbury in 1170.",
        "answer": "Thomas a Becket"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In a bronze sculpture depicting this war, a group of men walk toward the right behind the title commander on horseback; that sculpture is by Augustus Saint-Gaudens. Timothy O’Sullivan photographed The Harvest of Death during this war, during which Mathew Brady photographed many battlefields. Winslow Homer documented this conflict through illustrations like “The Army of the Potomac.” For ten points, name this war that inspired the Gettysburg Cyclorama.",
        "answer": "American Civil War"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Winslow Homer was commissioned by this New York-based magazine that employed cartoonist Thomas Nast and produced images like Boss Tweed as a vulture.",
        "answer": "Harper’s Weekly"
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Martin Luther King Jr.",
      "prompt": "In what city did...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "he give his “I Have a Dream” speech at the Lincoln Memorial?",
          "answer": "Washington D.C."
        },
        {
          "question": "he write “Injustice anywhere is a threat to justice everywhere” while in jail in Alabama?",
          "answer": "Birmingham"
        },
        {
          "question": "he support an Alabama bus boycott sparked by Rosa Parks?",
          "answer": "Montgomery"
        },
        {
          "question": "he lead a march across the Edmund Pettus Bridge?",
          "answer": "Selma"
        },
        {
          "question": "he support striking sanitation workers in Tennessee before being assassinated?",
          "answer": "Memphis"
        },
        {
          "question": "crowds, upset at his death, not riot after being calmed by an impromptu Robert Kennedy speech?",
          "answer": "Indianapolis"
        },
        {
          "question": "he move to North Lawndale in 1966 to support open housing?",
          "answer": "Chicago"
        },
        {
          "question": "King support Robert Hayling’s movement, which included a “dive-in” at the Monson Motor Lodge swimming pool?",
          "answer": "St. Augustine"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Joan of Arc",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Country she supported against England in the Hundred Years” War.",
          "answer": "France"
        },
        {
          "question": "City whose siege she relieved, catapulting her to fame.",
          "answer": "Orleans"
        },
        {
          "question": "Method by which she was executed.",
          "answer": "burning at the stake"
        },
        {
          "question": "Crime she was executed for which she committed by disguising herself.",
          "answer": "cross-dressing"
        },
        {
          "question": "Monarch who supported Joan and was crowned in Reims [RONCE] Cathedral in 1429.",
          "answer": "Charles VII"
        },
        {
          "question": "City, the stronghold for the English, where she was temporarily imprisoned.",
          "answer": "Rouen"
        },
        {
          "question": "Town in northern France where she was captured.",
          "answer": "Compiegne"
        },
        {
          "question": "Faction that captured her, supporters of John the Fearless.",
          "answer": [
            "Burgundians",
            "Burgundy"
          ]
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "20th Century Iran",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Capital city, where parts of the Golestan Palace were destroyed to make room for new buildings.",
          "answer": "Tehran"
        },
        {
          "question": "Neighboring country that invaded it in 1980.",
          "answer": "Iraq"
        },
        {
          "question": "Native, millenia-old religion that was given special protections under the Constitution of 1906.",
          "answer": "Zoroastrianism"
        },
        {
          "question": "Leader of the 1979 revolution who transformed Iran into an Islamic state.",
          "answer": [
            "Ruhollah Khomeini",
            "Ayatollah Khomeini"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Leader overthrown in that revolution, the last Shah of Iran.",
          "answer": [
            "Mohammad Reza Pahlavi",
            "either",
            "both names"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Color that names a reforming “Revolution” in the 60s and 70s under the last Shah.",
          "answer": "White Revolution"
        },
        {
          "question": "Popular Prime Minister who was overthrown in a 1953 CIA coup.",
          "answer": "Mohammad Mosaddegh"
        },
        {
          "question": "Secret police trained by the CIA and Mossad.",
          "answer": "SAVAK"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Three bright arcs around this object were named for the motto of the French Revolution. George Airy was blamed for the British team failure to discover this object first after Johann Galle used calculations by Urbain Le (20 pts)",
        "Verrier to do so. This planet, whose largest moon is Triton, was the final one visited by Voyager 2, which observed a Great (10 pts)",
        "Dark Spot on it. For ten points, name this planet that, after the demotion of Pluto, regained its status as the farthest planet from the Sun."
      ],
      "answer": "Neptune"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man wrote about the noble savage Hayy in his treatise The Christian Philosopher , the first book of science published in the Americas. This man, whose father served as President of (20 pts)",
        "Harvard for two decades and fought against governor-dictator Edmund Andros, supported smallpox inoculation in New England. The (10 pts)",
        "executions of colonists during the Salem Witch Trials were supported by, for ten points, what son of Increase, a Puritan minister during the First Great Awakening?"
      ],
      "answer": "Cotton Mather"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) John Stuart Mill claimed that this battle, “even as an event in British history, is more important than the Battle of Hastings.” Ctesias [tee-sus] and Herodotus disagree over whether a general who had earlier sacked Eretria, Datis, was (20 pts)",
        "killed at this battle. Eleven Plataeans were killed at this battle, where troops of the Leontis tribe were commanded by Themistocles. (10 pts)",
        "Miltiades [mill-TIE-uh-deez] led the winners of this battle, after which Pheidippides [fay-uh-DIP-uh-deez] delivered the news to Athens. For ten points, name this 490 BC battle that inspired a modern 26 mile race."
      ],
      "answer": "Battle of Marathon"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This philosopher once studied under the Earl of Shaftesbury, who he also served as a physician. In one book, this philosopher developed a theory of identity based on memory; in another book he argued for tolerance for everyone but Catholics and (20 pts)",
        "atheists. This author of A Letter Concerning Toleration developed the idea of the (10 pts)",
        "tabula rasa in An Essay Concerning Human Understanding. For ten points, name this English empiricist who defended the right to revolution in Two Treatises on Government."
      ],
      "answer": "John Locke"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The first battle in this conflict arose after merchants aboard the Thomas Coutts signed a trade bond despite orders to the contrary, prompting the (20 pts)",
        "Hyacinth and Volage to blockade a nearby town. During this war, a letter asking “where is your conscience” was addressed to one side’s monarch by Lin (10 pts)",
        "Zexu. This conflict ended in the Treaty of Nanking which ceded Hong Kong to Great Britain. The Qing were defeated in, for ten points, what 1839 war over the trade of a namesake drug."
      ],
      "answer": "First Opium War"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) The idea of an “infamous” crime as stated in this amendment is clarified in Green v. United States. Eminent domain with “just compensation” is allowed by this amendment’s Takings Clause, and another part of this amendment declares that (20 pts)",
        "life, liberty and property cannot be deprived without due process. Miranda warnings are required for this amendment’s right against (10 pts)",
        "self incrimination to be upheld. Defendants may plead, for ten points, what early Constitutional amendment that deals with criminal procedure?"
      ],
      "answer": "5th Amendment to the US Constitution"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This composer wrote a theme and variations for piano and orchestra on Mozart’s aria “L`a ci darem la mano.” This composer wrote a piano piece in response to the revolutions of 1848 that was nicknamed (20 pts)",
        "“Heroic” by his lover, George Sand. This composer’s personal response to the 1831 November Uprising was his (10 pts)",
        "E´tude on the Bombardment of Warsaw. For ten points, name this foremost composer of mazurkas, the Polish-born composer of the Minute Waltz and Revolutionary E´tude."
      ],
      "answer": "Fr´ed´eric Fran¸cois Chopin"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This monarch negotiated the return of Calais by signing the Treaty of Vervins with Philip II. The Battle of Ivry, a decisive battle with the (20 pts)",
        "Catholic League, was won by this monarch. This man, after defeating the Duke of Guise, legendarily converted to Catholicism by saying that (10 pts)",
        "“Paris is well worth a mass.” The Bourbon Dynasty was founded by this man who ended the French Wars of Religion. For ten points, name this French King who granted Huguenots religious freedom in the Edict of Nantes."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Henry IV of France",
        "Good King Henry",
        "Henry the Great",
        "Henry III of Navarre"
      ]
    }
  ]
}